Welcome into Road to the Draft, powered
by Microsoft Copilot. [music] In today's
episode, senior writer and editor Scott
Smith highlights how free agency
affected the needs of the teams picking
in [music] the top 10 and introduces you
to two new defensive prospects for the
Bucs to keep an eye on at 15.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Thank you, Casey, and we are rounding
the bend of another very significant
stretch in this road to the draft, and
that is, of course, the start [music] of
free agency. I'm sure you've heard
coaches say many times that pass rush
and pass coverage go hand in hand, and
in much the same way, free agency and
the draft go hand in hand when we're
talking about roster construction. Under
general manager Jason Licht, the
Buccaneers are very much a draft,
retain, [music]
draft, develop, and retain team, but
sometimes you do have to fill in the
gaps in free agency, and this year the
[music] Buccaneers have actually been a
bit more active in that regard than in
recent years. And in the first week or
so of free agency, you see the outside
players the Buccaneers have brought
[music] in, and a couple I'd like to
highlight because they could affect what
the Buccaneers do in the draft. Some of
the positions that the Buccaneers are
predicted to emphasize early in the
draft are off-ball linebacker, and you
see Al added a starter in Alex Anzalone,
uh edge rusher, and we see Al Quadin
Muhammad here at 11 sacks last year for
Detroit. And then defensive line,
A'Shawn Robinson with the departure of
Logan Hall. He can step right in there
next to Vita Vea and Calijah Kancey. So,
does that affect what the Buccaneers
will do in the draft? I'm not sure. I
think this could be a situation where
what you did was you provided yourself
flexibility, so you're not forced into a
specific position, but you could still
see the Buccaneers doubling up at any of
these positions. Kind of like last year,
when they needed edge rush help, and not
only signed uh Haason Reddick, but still
felt like they needed to go after the
position in the draft with David [music]
Walker. So, this helps us inform us of
what the Bucs might do, but I don't
think it's the whole picture.
And of course, the Buccaneers weren't
the only team making moves in the first
week of free agency. There were a lot of
players that changed teams over that
week, and uh maybe more than we can keep
track of. So, we asked for Copilot's
help because we thought we would look at
what the teams in the top 10 [music] in
the draft did, and see if that affects
what they might do before the Buccaneers
at pick number 15. Uh we start with the
Raiders, of course. They did a lot, uh
but I don't think any of that would
change the fact [music] that they're
taking Fernando Mendoza. As we scroll
down here, you're going to see that a
lot of these teams added an edge rusher,
which [music] is relevant to the
Buccaneers, such as Joseph Ossai. They
also signed Kingsley Enagbare, the Jets
did. The Cardinals did not pick up one.
Uh I think I want to focus here [music]
on the Tennessee Titans because they did
a lot in free agency as well. They had
the most cap space available, but what
you don't see here is a running back.
They added a lot, but not a running
back, and that has fueled [music] a lot
of speculation that they'll go with
Jeremiah Love here at pick number four.
You see here, uh we go down now, um
Cleveland, [music]
widely expected to take an offensive
lineman early in the draft, but they did
sign three starters, so they're not
necessarily locked into that.
>> [music]
>> And then here we see Washington, also an
edge rusher, important to the
Buccaneers, plus an off-ball linebacker.
>> [music]
>> Uh and then we get to the New Orleans
Saints. Uh I think the key here is the
signing of Travis Etienne, as it's now
pronounced, uh which [music] means they
probably thought Jeremiah Love would not
be available by pick eight. What you do
not see here is a wide receiver, which
is a big [music] need for the Saints. Uh
next to Chris Olave, you got Tyler Shuck
now,
>> [music]
>> you got Travis Etienne, and if they pick
a receiver, a real good duo there, so
that's a little scary for the
Buccaneers.
>> [music]
>> Also, the Chiefs also signed a running
back. Uh they don't think that Jeremiah
Love's going to be here. And again,
Cincinnati with uh [music] signing Boye
Mafe to a really big contract. So, what
I think that means to the Buccaneers
[music] in total is an idea of which
teams might not be as desperate to take
[music] an edge rusher as they were
before the start of free agency.
Okay, now that we've looked at how free
agency could affect the first 14 picks
[music] before the Buccaneers, let's
take a look at a couple more players
that might be available at pick number
15, [music]
starting with Miami edge rusher Adkeem
Mesidor. This is a guy [music] whose
stock we've seen rise quite a bit in
mock drafts in recent weeks. 6-3, 259,
so he has good size. It's a player with
a relentless motor, and he's also kind
of a nice bounce because he he can
convert speed to power, has real good
bull rush, but also pretty nice uh
repertoire [music] of pass rush moves,
including kind of like a basketball
Eurostep that he uses to confuse [music]
offensive tackles. He's just a mauler
and an uh relentless motor type of guy,
so I think he's a a player that uh
defensive coaches would like quite a
bit. Now, another guy is Tennessee
cornerback Kool-Aid McKinstry. It's my
personal philosophy that you can never
have enough uh quality cornerback depth,
and of course, the Buccaneers lost Jamel
Dean in free agency. [music] Uh so,
we're looking at Kool-Aid McKinstry,
one of two
Tennessee [music] You see 6-0, 193, so
he's got good size and length for the
position, and he ran really well at the
combine, ran a 4.44 [music]
40-yard dash, a real nice 10-second
split, was great in the vertical leap
and the broad jump, so he's a very
athletic guy, was productive for
Tennessee, [music] and with the loss of
Jamel Dean, you cannot rule out the idea
that the Buccaneers could go cornerback
in the first round. [music] So, there's
two more uh prospects that could be of
interest to the Buccaneers at pick
number 15. [music]
This has been Road to the Draft, powered
by Copilot. We're going to be here with
you all the way leading up to the draft,
so we'll see you next time.
>> [music]